# Alireza Mashayekhi

### **Front-end Engineer**

+989924098979 / maalireza51@gmail.com / linkedin.com/in/alireza-mashayekhi / Tehran, Iran (open to relocation)

## **Summary**

Front-end developer with **5+ years of experience** designing and building **responsive web design** for a variety of devices considering different types of industries. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with **extensive knowledge of UX and customer experience**. Notable achievements include **boosting the conversion rate** of an existing website by 60% with improved code and design. Able to **effectively lead tasks and mentor junior members** of the team.

## **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript (ES6+) | TypeScript

Web Frameworks and Libraries: Next.js | React | Vite | Cypress | Jest | Testing Library | GraphQL

**Additional Tools and Technologies**: MicroFrontend, Apollo, Redux, MaterialUI, TailwindCSS, Ant Design, PWA, Git, GitlabCI/CD, Docker, NestJS, Node.js, LocalStack (AWS)

## **Work Experience**

#### **Front-end Software Engineer**

Shab (Short-term house rental marketplace) - Tehran, Iran - February 2023–Present

TypeScript, MicroFrontend, Next.js, React, Redux, Redux-Thunk, MaterialUI, PWA, REST API, Leaflet, Jest, Testing Library, Heap analytics, Node.js, Express Figma, Trello, Git, Docker

- Transformed search experience by improving maps using Leaflet. It leads to a 40% increase in user engagement and 10% search to product conversion rate measured by heap analytics.
- Reduced first-load bundle size of home page by 20% through the implementation of webp image format.
- Provided specialized tools to monitor OKRs and analytics, Caused 20% improvement in goals alignment and performance tracking like A/B testing.
- Collaborated with designers to construct a new design system based on MaterialUI.
- Implemented progressive web application to have app-like look and performance improvements.
- Experienced mentoring other front-end developers.
- Agile worked by using Trello as task management and worked closely with product managers and designers.

#### **Front-end Engineer**

Qmoil (Recycling oil warehouses automation) - Tehran, Iran - November 2021–December 2022

Next.js, React, Vite, MicroFrontend, Redux-toolkit, REST API, TailwindCSS, Ant Design, Jest, Git, Docker, CI/CD

- Created automation admin panel from A to Z in order to monitor 4 warehouses.
- Integrated data visualization libraries and charts (Chart.js) into the admin panel to reduce the time required to analyze complex datasets.
- Configured micro frontend by editing Vite configs.
- Facilitated asynchronous data fetching by using state management (Redux-toolkit) to maintain data consistency.
- Dockerized the project to ensure seamless deployment and consistency across different environments.

## **Front-end Developer**

Dekatech (IoT platform) - Tehran, Iran - April 2020-October 2021

React, Bootstrap, JQuery, Responsive design, REST API, Socket, Node.js, Git, Github

- Developed admin panel and landing by converting 15 JQuery pages to React.
- Used both Socket and HTTP to create connections between devices and host.
- Established responsive design and development using AdobeXD
- Worked nearly with hardware engineers to prototype and test IoT solutions. Validating functionalities into the panel.

#### Web Developer

Freelance - January 2018-March 2022

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Responsive design, CMS, Git, Photoshop

- Built and tested pages for presenting +30 ecommerce templates.
- Streamlined client workflows by providing guidance on website content management systems, Resulting in a 25% reduction in unnecessary communication and increased client autonomy.
- Successfully developed corporate and eCommerce websites for 10+ clients.
- Consulted with clients to understand their business needs and recommended the most suitable web solutions.
- Crafted a CV template from photoshop design to list in Themeforest.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Electronics Engineer - Urmia university (September 2015–July 2019)

#### Language